Russel Wright Papers
Russel Wright Papers
- Clients and products
  - Shwayder Brothers, Inc.
    - School furniture
      - Presentation sketches (Box 27)
      - Questionnaire, school color (Box 27)
      - Rejected design sketches (Box 27)
      - Research notes (Box 27)
      - Specifications and catalogue (Box 27)
      - Standards, N.Y.C. (Box 27)
      - Tables, sketches (Box 27)
      - Tablet arm (Box 27)
      - Teachers desks (Box 27)
      - Technical and consultation (Box 27)
      - Void drawings (Box 27)
    - Vinyl pattern suggestions (Oversize 29)
  - Simtex Mills tablecloths (Box 27)
  - Silex Company
    - Alcohol stove, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - China coffeemaker (Box 27)
    - Factory blueprints (Box 27)
  - Ski lodge
    - Cardboard model, See Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 24).
    - Preliminary drawings (Box 27)
  - Slesinger residence
    - Fenestration (Box 27)
    - Preliminary drawings, exterior (Box 27)
    - Preliminary drawings, interior (Box 27)
    - Rough drawings (Box 27)
    - Studies (Box 27)
    - Studies, land (Box 27)
  - Sloan Blabon Corporation
    - Competitors (Box 28)
    - Designs
      - Bubbles, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Close cross strips (Box 28)
      - Color sample (Box 28)
      - Color, tropical (Box 28)
      - Cross scratch (Box 28)
      - Native leaves (Box 28)
      - Plaid (Box 28)
      - Squares (Box 28)
      - Wide cross strips (Box 28)
      - Ideas (Box 28)
      - Ideas not used (Box 28)
      - Ideas rejected (Box 28)
      - Catalog [of] linoleum products (Box 28)
      - Colors, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Designs, Sloan's and others (Box 28)
    - Drawings, tropical leaves (Box 28)
    - Notes
      - Conference (Box 28)
      - Experiments in vinyl calendering (Box 28)
      - Factory production (Box 28)
      - Limitations to enamel printing (Box 28)
      - Sales (Box 28)
    - Studies, tropical pattern (Box 28)
  - Sovereign Clover decoration prelims (Box 28)
  - Sovereign Potteries, Ltd.
    - Casserole cover (Box 28)
    - Cereal bowl (Box 28)
    - Decoration sketches (Box 28)
    - Creamer (Box 28)
    - Cup fired size (Box 28)
    - Cup and saucer (Box 28)
    - Jam jar (Box 28)
    - Gravy stand (Box 28)
    - Photos (Box 28)
    - Plates (Box 28)
    - RW and MW logo (Box 28)
    - Salt and pepper (Box 28)
    - Sugar bowl (Box 28)
    - Tea pot (Box 28)
    - Total relation (Box 28)
  - Stacking refrigerator (Box 28)
  - Stage setting, "Taming Appliances" theater design (Oversize 43)
  - Stage settings (Box 28)
  - Stanton (Box 28)
  - Statton Furniture Mfg. Company
    - [General], 1949-1952 (Box 28)
    - Bedroom
      - Bed with high dropleaf (Box 28)
      - Beds (Box 28)
      - Cheap headboard (Box 28)
      - Chest and drawer pulls (Box 28)
      - Chest cut outs (Box 28)
      - Conventional night table (Box 28)
      - Daybed with pitched seat (Box 28)
      - Decorative plans (Box 28)
      - Night table with tray or slide (Box 28)
      - Porcelain night table (Box 28)
      - 3 drawer chest (Box 29)
      - 6 drawer chest (Box 29)
    - Dining room
      - Chairs
        - Hardwood seat (Box 29)
        - New slip seat side chair (Box 29)
        - Sketches (Box 29)
        - Slip seat (Box 29)
      - Large dining table (Box 29)
      - New 40"x60" dining table (Box 29)
      - Pieces (Box 29)
      - Side chair (Box 29)
    - Drawings
      - S 71 (Box 29)
      - S 72, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Furniture, miscellaneous, See Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 1).
    - Fabrics
      - Cheap cotton base (Box 29)
      - Denim
        - Colors (Box 29)
        - Cream and black (Box 29)
        - Dark aqua (Box 29)
        - Dark blue (Box 29)
        - Dark green (Box 29)
        - Lime (Box 29)
        - Olive (Box 29)
        - Orange brown (Box 29)
        - Patchogue (Box 29)
      - Extra samples (Box 29)
      - Goat hair lining (Box 29)
      - Heavy texture (Box 29)
      - Houndstooth, woven (Box 29)
      - Ideas for special fabrics (Box 29)
      - Research, Chicopee Mfg. Company of Georgia, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Research, silver drawer lining (Box 29)
      - RW upholstery (Box 29)
      - Saran (Box 29)
      - Scots-Wai houndstooth (Box 30)
      - Simtex tablecloth (Box 30)
      - Sycamore color samples (Box 30)
      - Vinyls (Box 30)
      - Washable terry cloth (Box 30)
    - Living room
      - Bedroom chest combinations (Box 30)
      - Chairs - TV - small (Box 30)
      - Coffee table (Box 30)
      - Corner table (Box 30)
      - Desk chairs - innovation - new design (Box 30)
      - End table - drop leaves (Box 30)
      - End table with drawers (Box 30)
      - Extension card table (Box 30)
      - Front room couch (Box 30)
      - Knock down book cases (Box 30)
      - Magazine rack and service cart (Box 30)
      - Nested table (Box 30)
      - New extension coffee table (Box 30)
      - New pieces (Box 30)
      - New studio couch (Box 30)
      - New upholstered pieces (Box 30)
      - Ottoman (Box 30)
      - Sectional bookcase (Box 30)
      - 60" Sabutan unit- sketches (Box 30)
      - Smoke table (Box 30)
      - Sofa - "Old Hickory" file (Box 30)
      - Studio couch (Box 30)
      - Studio couch #2 (Box 30)
      - 2 pedestal desk (Box 30)
      - TV unit - Pandannus weave (Box 30)
      - Upholstered arm chair (Box 30)
    - New sketches
      - Arm chair (Box 30)
      - Armless reclining (Box 30)
      - Arms - RW chair (Box 30)
      - Kramer sketches (Box 30)
      - Bedroom
        - Dresser without innovations (Box 30)
        - Mr. Chest (Box 30)
        - Mrs. Dresser or chest (Box 30)
        - Vanity (Box 30)
      - Cabinet or single pedestal chest (Box 30)
      - Card table (Box 30)
      - Coffee table (Box 30)
      - Corner table (Box 30)
      - Dining room chest (Box 30)
      - Drop leaf table (Box 30)
      - Easy chair (type B) (Box 30)
      - End cabinet (Box 30)
      - Headboard for studio bed (Box 30)
      - Individual easy chairs (Box 30)
      - Innovation cocktail table (Box 30)
      - Innovation night table (Box 30)
      - Knock down bookshelves (Box 30)
      - Lamp table (Box 30)
      - Living room - sectional sofa - type A (Box 31)
      - Night table (Box 31)
      - Reading or reclining chair (Box 31)
      - Slip seat chair (Box 31)
      - Side chair (Box 31)
      - Sofa - studio bed (Box 31)
      - Swinging TV chair (Box 31)
    - Notes
      - Construction - design studio (Box 31)
      - Construction - final detail drawings (Box 31)
      - Presentation (Box 31)
      - Statton Furniture line (Box 31)
    - Reference material
      - Bed room
        - Chest or innovation night table (Box 31)
        - Chest without innovation (Box 31)
        - Mr. And Mrs. Chests (Box 31)
      - Dining room
        - Case goods (Box 31)
        - Jr. group
          - Matching (Box 31)
          - Side chair (Box 31)
          - Table (Box 31)
      - Innovation pieces
        - Cab. Or single prd. Desk (Box 31)
        - Cocktail table (Box 31)
        - Console extension table (Box 31)
      - Living room
        - Case goods
          - Coffee table (Box 31)
          - Corner table (Box 31)
          - Lamp table (Box 31)
        - Sofa (Box 31)
        - Type B matching chair (Box 31)
        - Type B sofa (Box 31)
        - Type B sectional sofa (Box 31)
      - Occasional seating
        - Easy chair (Box 31)
        - Swinging chair (Box 31)
    - Research
      - Antiques (Box 31)
      - Caster (Box 31)
      - Colors for tables
        - Chicago vitreous enamel, 4 folders (Box 31)
        - Seaporcel Metals, Inc., 6 folders (Box 31)
      - Competitors
        - Conan and Ball (Box 31)
        - Lewittes and Sons (Box 31)
      - Drapery fabrics for display, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Fabric mfgs. (Box 31)
      - Hardware and misc. (Box 31)
      - Market (Box 31)
      - Picture search (Box 31)
      - Product "curled hair" (Box 31)
      - Showroom (Box 31)
      - Showroom accessories (Box 31)
      - Showroom Caribbean accessories (Box 31)
      - Showroom Grand Rapids (Box 32)
      - Table top
        - Finishes (Box 32)
        - Follow up (Box 32)
        - Materials (Box 32)
      - Television (Box 32)
      - Versibond, statusply, and plastic (Box 32)
      - Wood (Box 32)
    - Research material - table tops (Box 32)
    - Sales presentation (Box 32)
    - Sales promotion (Box 32)
      See Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 9).
    - Studies
      - Alternate base (Box 32)
      - Alternate doors to vertical door nit (Box 32)
      - Colors and sketches (Box 32)
      - Comprehensive Fabrics, Inc., 4 folders (Box 32)
      - Drawings (Box 32)
      - Drawings - miscellaneous (Box 32)
      - "Easier Living" (Box 32)
      - Elevations
        - Final changes (Box 32)
        - For pictures (Box 32)
        - Showroom (Box 32)
        - Walls "P" and "B" (Box 32)
      - Fabric houses - bills (Box 32)
      - Floor plans - showroom Grand Rapids
        - 1950 (Box 32)
        - 1946-1951 (Box 32)
      - Final drawings - numbered (Box 32)
      - Final drawings - numbered - large folder (Box 33)
      - Full scale roughs (Box 33)
      - Full scale roughs - large folder (Box 33)
      - Leg (Box 33)
      - Lobby - furniture layouts (Box 33)
      - Miscellaneous details (Box 33)
      - "Modernage"
        - Antique accessories (Box 33)
        - Data (Box 33)
        - Final drawings (Box 33)
        - Floor coverings (Box 33)
        - Floor layout (Box 33)
        - Floor plan (Box 33)
        - Furniture layouts
          - Space A (Box 33)
          - Space B (Box 33)
          - Space E and F (Box 33)
          - Space G, H, I, J (Box 33)
        - General information (Box 33)
        - Show window (Box 33)
        - Show window renderings and drawings (Box 33)
      - Preliminary full scale sketches (Box 33)
      - Presentation drawings (Box 33)
      - Showroom
        - Final list of furnishings (Box 33)
        - Final samples of fabrics, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Sofa construction (Box 33)
      - Tracings of new items (Box 33)
  - Sterling China Company
    - Catalogs (Box 34)
    - Conference notes, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Factory drawings (Box 34)
    - Factory notes (Box 34)
    - Final drawings (Box 34)
    - Four seasons (Box 34)
    - Glaze experiments (Box 34)
    - Pattern #1 finished plaster (Box 34)
    - Pattern #1 sketches (Box 34)
    - Pattern #2 finished plaster (Box 34)
    - Pattern #2 sketches (Box 34)
    - Pitcher and coffee bottle studies (Box 34)
    - Polynesian (Box 34)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 34)
    - Presentation drawings, not used, See Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 17).
    - Revised water pitcher (Box 34)
    - Sources: Interim design materials (Box 34)
    - "Suede" pamphlet (Box 34)
    - Theme 1, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Theme 2, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Theme 4, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Theme 6, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Theme 7, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Theme 11, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Theme 12, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Vitreous restaurant ware (Box 34)
    - Wright Accessories (Box 34)
    - Wright Accessories magazine clippings (Oversize 25)
  - Steubenville
    - Abstract decorated (Box 34)
    - American Modern color trials, 1955 (Box 34)
    - American Modern decorations, grass (Box 34)
    - Beaker (Box 34)
    - Beaker theme "59" (Box 34)
    - Black glaze experiments (Box 34)
    - Butter dish studies (Box 34)
    - Chart (Box 34)
    - Chosen theme (Box 34)
    - Correspondence (Box 34)
    - Cushion (Box 34)
    - Design (Box 34)
    - Dinnerware, infant (Box 34)
    - Glazes, wartime (Box 34)
    - New butter dishes (Box 34)
    - New items to be modeled (Box 34)
    - New item sketches (Box 34)
    - Oval (Box 34)
    - Oval theme (Box 34)
    - Pottery sketches, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Replaced models, 1943 (Box 34)
    - Revised cup and handle (Box 34)
    - Ricket (Box 34)
    - TV plate studies (Box 34)
    - Wood cover drawings (Box 34)
  - Stove to tableware
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Handles and knobs, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Edges (Box 35)
    - Flame protectors (Box 35)
  - Studio Plus, crescent swivel joints (Box 35)
  - Sutherland
    - Abstracts (Box 35)
    - Blanks (Box 35)
    - Cup, bowls, plates (Box 35)
    - Emboss sketcher (Box 35)
    - Florals (Box 35)
    - Paper Company, 1959 (Box 35)
    - Paper Company, 1962 (Box 35)
    - Theme, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Sydney chairs, publicity photographs (Box 35)
  - Taiwan Children's Group Bamboo (Box 35)
  - Templates (Box 35)
  - Time sheets, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Tip tilt (Box 35)
  - Town & Country, country house studies (Box 35)
  - Trimount vending machines (Box 35)
  - Under sink storage (Box 35)
  - Unit furniture (Box 35)
  - University of Illinois Small Homes Council (Box 35)
  - United States Department of Agriculture (Box 35)
  - Vanity lamp, letters from Dept. of Commerce 1930's (Box 35)
  - Vegetable bin (Box 35)
  - Vending machines, 1933 (Box 35)
    See Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 23).
  - Vietnam Dept. store exhibit publicity, 1959 (Box 35)
    See Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 17).
  - Wastebaskets (Box 35)
  - Western Cooperative (Box 35)
  - White Clover, Parker [Harker?] (Box 35)
  - Wilkes Barre Lace Company
    - Showroom, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Loose drawings (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35)
  - Woodenware (Box 35)
  - Women's designs
    - Capes and coats (Box 36)
    - Dress fashions, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Hair-dos (Box 36)
    - Shoes (Box 36)
  - Wood springs (Box 36)
  - World's Fair, New York, focal food exhibit (Box 35)
    See also Oversize material: Miscellaneous (Oversize 1), and New York World's Fair (above).
  - World's Fair Parade, 1939 (Box 36)
  - Mary Wright pattern (Box 36)
  - Mary Wright museum sketches (Box 36)
  - Wurlitzer Piano Company
    - [General], 1932 (Box 36)
    - Accordion, 1931 (Box 36)
    - Accordion, piano and radio renderings, 1931-1932 (Box 36)
    - Accordion sketches, 1932 (Box 36)
- Writings
  - Biographical sketch of Russel Wright
  - Books
    - Easier Living (Box 37)
      - Appendix B (Box 37)
      - Chapters I-V, VII-IX, 9 folders (Box 37)
      - Chart for tablesetting (Box 37)
      - Charts (Box 37)
      - Illustrations, 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Illustrators (Box 37)
      - Incomplete galley proof (Box 37)
      - List and chart - illustrations (Box 37)
      - Notes (Box 37)
      - Original artwork, 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Research material (Box 37)
      - Table of contents, acknowledgements, appendix (Box 37)
      - What Is Easier Living? - galley proof (Box 37)
  - Lectures - selling (Box 37)
  - Manuals
    - Life Without Dorcas, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Articles/lectures
    - Albright Art Gallery (Box 38)
    - American Modern tour (Box 38)
    - American Way (Box 38)
    - Art and Antiques (Box 38)
    - Art school lectures on Industrial Design, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - B (Box 38)
    - Bamboo Group HANO housewares (Box 38)
    - Better Living article (Box 38)
    - Biographical material (Box 38)
    - "Building a Dream House: The Story of Dragon Rock" (Box 38)
    - Chicago Art Institute (Box 38)
    - Crockery and Glass (Box 38)
    - Dayton Panel - March 30th (Box 38)
    - Design Derby, Miami -, 1958 (Box 38)
    - DuPont Magazine (Box 38)
    - Eating outdoors - then and now (Box 38)
    - Electrical Merchandizing Magazine (Box 38)
    - Entertaining fun with food - supper (Box 38)
    - Far East drafts (Box 38)
    - Far East slide show (Box 38)
    - Far East story drafts (Box 38)
    - Festival Press notes (Box 38)
    - Festival P.R. releases (Box 38)
    - Flower pot sizes (Box 38)
    - Garrison Landing publicity (Box 38)
    - Gas Appliance Manufacturers Association (Box 38)
    - Good Housekeeping Institute (Box 38)
    - Herald Tribune Bride's School (Box 38)
    - Home Fashions League (Box 38)
    - Hotel Bulletin (Box 38)
    - Ideas for articles (Box 38)
    - Industrial Design Magazine (Box 38)
    - Interior Design Magazine (Box 38)
    - Kitchen Cabinet Association meeting (Box 38)
    - List (Box 38)
    - Lists - dinnerware (Box 38)
    - Living for Young Homemakers (Box 38)
    - "Man in the Kitchen" ( Women's Home Companion) (Box 38)
    - "Manitoga" brochures (Box 38)
    - National Restaurant Association (Box 38)
    - News of Putnam County, 1966 (Box 38)
    - New York Herald Tribune "Don't Be a Phony" (Box 38)
    - New York Times 10/2/66 (Box 38)
    - New York Times article, 1961 (Box 38)
    - New York Times "Bamboo Bridge", 1961 (Box 38)
    - Notes - personal (Box 38)
    - Perfect Home article (Box 38)
    - Progressive Architect - School Furniture (Box 38)
    - Proposed R.W. and B. Webster lectures at New York University (Box 38)
    - Radio shows (old) (Box 38)
    - Radio and TV shows - 1950 on (Box 38)
    - Reference material - Affiliated Retailers - members (Box 38)
    - Reference material - appliances (electric) by others (Box 39)
    - Reference material - industrial designing (Box 39)
    - Retailing Daily (Box 39)
    - R.W. on internal vs. external designer (Box 39)
    - Articles by R.W. (Box 39)
    - Articles by R.W. - pending (Box 39)
    - Russel Wright Show (Box 39)
    - Sarna Aluminum items (Box 39)
    - Sarna conference notes (Box 39)
    - Speeches R.W. and trips, 1963 (Box 39)
    - Speeches by R.W. (old) (Box 39)
    - Speeches, trips for R.W. (Box 39)
    - Steel Kitchen Cabinet Manufacturers Association 3/55 (Box 39)
    - Table service slide lecture (Box 39)
    - Table setting - Mary Wright (1934-1950) (Box 39)
    - This week/ components and accessories (Box 39)
    - Time Magazine (Box 39)
    - Trade cards, letter to Ann Wright from Arthur Pulos (Box 39)
    - Trip to Japan - personal (Box 39)
    - Upholstering Magazine (Box 39)
    - Women's Wear Daily (Box 39)
- Correspondence/subject files
  - Architectural Forum (Box 40)
  - Advertising Age (Box 40)
  - American Home (Box 40)
  - Better Design Magazine (Box 40)
  - Better Homes and Gardens, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Better Living (Box 40)
  - China and glass (Box 40)
  - Correspondence with James Tillett (Box 40)
  - Cosmopolitan (Box 40)
  - Country Gentleman (Box 40)
  - Craft Horizons (Box 40)
  - Creative Playthings (Box 40)
  - DuPont - sales research correspondence (Box 40)
  - Electrical manufacturing (Box 40)
  - Glamour Magazine (Box 40)
  - Good Housekeeping (Box 40)
  - Home Furnishing (Box 40)
  - House Beautiful (Box 40)
  - Housewares Review (Box 40)
  - Interiors (Box 40)
  - Iroquois, 10 folders (Box 40)
  - Lamp Journal (Box 40)
  - Letter from Don Wallace (Box 40)
  - Letters 1955 and survey (Box 40)
  - Letters to Wright, 1955 (Box 40)
  - Lifetime Living (Box 40)
  - Living life (Box 40)
  - Longbell, 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 40)
  - Modern Metals (Box 40)
  - New Yorker (Box 40)
  - New York Times (Box 40)
  - Northern Industrial Chemical Company (Box 40)
  - Pageant (Box 40)
  - Parade (Box 40)
  - Parents (Box 40)
  - Press (Box 40)
  - Printers (Box 40)
  - Reader's Digest (Box 40)
  - Red Book (Box 40)
  - Shun Lee (Box 40)
  - Simon and Schuster (Box 40)
  - This Week (Box 40)
  - Time (Box 40)
  - Upholstering (Box 40)
  - Wormley, Edward J. (Box 40)
- Surveys
  - American brides (Box 41)
  - Cattails for drapes (Box 41)
  - China (Box 41)
  - Colgate aircraft (Box 41)
  - Home entertaining (Box 41)
  - Home of tomorrow
    - Architectural style (Box 41)
    - Bedrooms (Box 41)
    - Contest (Box 41)
    - Dining rooms (Box 41)
    - Kitchen (Box 41)
    - Living rooms (Box 41)
  - Linens
    - Bromley (Box 41)
    - Cohn-Hall-Marx Company -, 1947; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Cohn-Hall-Marx Company questionnaire replies, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Cohn-Hall-Marx Company table size questionnaire (Box 41)
    - Rosemary - sales (Box 41)
  - Manufacturer's research (Box 41)
  - Metal furniture - Colgate Aircraft (Box 41)
  - Metal furniture - Colgate Aircraft - questionnaire replies (Box 41)
  - Plastic - DuPont (Box 41)
  - Plastic tableware - General American Transportation (Box 42)
  - Pottery (Box 42)
  - Questionnaire forms, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Rugs - art loom rugs (Box 42)
  - Soft goods - DuPont (Box 42)
  - Taiwan Handicraft Promotion Center (Box 42)
- Foreign activities
  - Asia and Far East (Box 43)
  - Cambodia, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Cambodia photos, 4 folders (Box 43)
  - Cambodia reception for king (Box 43)
  - Chinese designs (Box 43)
  - Dominican Republic
    - Cow hide chair (Box 43)
    - International trade (Box 43)
    - Research (Box 43)
    - Wood project (Box 43)
  - Exhibition photos, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Far East notes (Box 43)
  - General press conference at Carnegie Foundation (Box 43)
  - I.C.A.
    - 1959 - overhead working papers (Box 43)
    - 1960 - overhead working papers (Box 43)
    - Overhead final papers - 1958, 1959, 1960 (Box 43)
    - Publicity, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Taiwan
      - Bamboo (Box 43)
      - Liquor baskets (Box 43)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 43)
      - Petterson (Box 43)
      - Samovar liner (Box 43)
      - Sarna (Box 43)
        - Drawings (Box 43)
        - Hwo-Gwo (Box 43)
        - Rough drafting (Box 43)
        - Sketches (Box 43)
      - Sohn (Box 43)
      - Sohn sketches (Box 43)
      - Sohn specifications (Box 43)
    - Japan industrial designers (Box 43)
    - Japan project lists (Box 43)
  - Laos (Box 44)
  - Materials for industrial design consultant project (Box 44)
  - Nepal (Box 44)
  - Nikko exhibition (Box 44)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 44)
  - Report on consultation - Japanese electrical household goods (Box 44)
  - Report on Japanese export goods (Box 44)
  - Russel Wright Associates photo album of Cambodian, Thai and Vietnamese products (Box 44)
  - Selected bibliographies on manual industry (Box 44)
  - Taiwan
    - Bamboo adhesives (Box 44)
    - Bamboo processing, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Display shelves (Box 44)
    - Formosa fibre samples (Box 44)
    - Grass adhesives (Box 44)
    - Lightolin collapsible lamp (Box 44)
    - Sarna rough drafting (Box 44)
    - Sheet projects (Box 44)
    - Shop (Box 44)
  - Thailand (Box 44)
  - USOM annual report (Box 45)
  - Vegetable fibers and their uses (Box 45)
  - Vietnam, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Vietnam
    - CUSA-ICSA (Box 45)
    - Final report (Box 45)
    - Manual for handicraft import promotion (Box 45)
    - Photos, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Publicity (Box 45)
    - Reclaim, 1960 (Box 45)
    - Russel Wright material (Box 45)
    - Saigon shop (Box 45)
- Contracts
  - Aaron, Howard S. (Box 46)
  - Acme Fluorescent Company, Inc., Acme Lamp (Box 46)
  - Aluminum Goods Manufacturing Company (Box 46)
  - American Crystal Company (Box 46)
  - American Cyanamid Company (Box 46)
  - American Olean Tile Company (Box 46)
  - Amplex Corporation (Box 46)
  - Amtra Trading Company (Box 46)
  - Appleman Art Glass Works (Box 46)
  - Arden Jewelry Case Manufacturing Company (Box 46)
  - Aristocrat Leather Products (Box 46)
  - Art Loom Carpet Company, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Aulicino, Armand D. (Box 46)
  - Baker, Lockwood Manufacturing Company (Box 46)
  - Barbieri, Guido (Box 46)
  - Bartlett-Collins Company (Box 46)
  - Bauer Pottery Company (Box 46)
  - Beinert, John (Box 46)
  - Bennett Associates (Box 46)
  - Birnback, Carl (Box 46)
  - Bleeker, John and son (Box 46)
  - Bowes Industries (Box 46)
  - Bufkor, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Buhl, Einar A. (Box 46)
  - Calvert Distillers Company (Box 46)
  - Camar Pottery Company (Box 46)
  - Campbell Soup Company (Box 46)
  - Candullo, Joseph (Box 46)
  - Capital Roofing (Box 46)
  - Carson, Margaret, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Cashin, Bonnie (Box 46)
  - Century Metalcraft Company (Box 46)
  - Chase Brass and Copper Company (Box 46)
  - Cohn - Hall - Marx Company (Box 46)
  - Colgate Aircraft Company (Box 46)
  - Colon, Fred (Box 46)
  - Colonial - Premier Company (Box 46)